Guide to the Ted Fagan Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Reel to reel tapes
  - Basses and Baritones, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 59)
    (Taped from discs) Strienz, Wilhelm, bass. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Entführung aus dem Serail. Vivat Bacchus; Wer ein Liebchen hat gefunden -- Kneip. Schwalbenlied -- Witherspoon, Herbert, 1873-1935, bass. Henrion, Paul. Mulletier de Tarragon -- Homer, Sidney, 1864-1953. Requiem, Op. 15, No.2 -- Dearest, Op.24 -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Unidentified Passion music -- Stracciari, Riccardo, baritone. de Curtis. Parlatemi d' amore -- Hüsch, Gerhard, baritone. Hermann, Hans, 1870-1931. Salomo; Poet speaks -- Kilpinen, Yrjö. Alte Kirche; Moor; Tunturilauluja
  - Stradella, Alessandro, 1639-1682. Forza dell'amor paterno., 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 60)
    Valletti, Cesare, tenor
  - Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955. Jeanne d'Arc au bûcher, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 61)
    Bernstein, Felicia, singer; Singher, Martial, baritone; Addison, Adele, singer; Price, Leontyne, soprano; Bible, Frances, mezzo-soprano; Lloyd, David, tenor; Alvary, Lorenzo, 1909-, baritone. Westminster Chorus and Columbus Boys' Chorus. New York Philharmonic Orchestra. Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990, conductor
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911- Amelia al ballo and Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948. Segreto di Susanna, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 62)
    (Taped from discs) Carosio, Margherita, 1908-2005, as Amelia; Panerai, Rolando, as the husband; Pradelli, Giacinto, the lover. Teatro alla Scala. Orchestra and Chorus. Sanzogno, Nino, conductor. Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1911- Amelia al ballo -- Rizzieri, Elena, as Susana; Valdengo, Giuseppe, 1914- as St. Gil. Radiotelevisione italiana. Orchestra sinfonica di Torino. Questa, A, conductor. Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948. Segreto di Susanna
  - Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931, soprano. Farewell performance, Covent Garden. June 8, 1927, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 63)
    With Brownlee, John, 1868-1927, baritone. Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Bohème. Donde lieta uscì; with Mummery, Browning, tenor. Addio, dolce svegliare; Sono andati? -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Piangea cantando; Ave Maria -- Address of Lord Stanley -- Address of Melba, Nellie, Dame -- Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1885. Hamlet. Selection -- Lotti, Antonio, d. 1740. Pur dicesti, o bocca bella
  - Is this the UN, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 64)
    Song to the UN -- Psse. Ping-Pong of Cambodia and her "Explanation of Vote" -- Krishna Menon, V. K. (Vengalil Krishnan), 1897-1974. Gobbly-dook (sic) interview; "Hatching speech"; "Withdrawal scene" on the Kashmir issue -- illegible (see card index)
  - Private (Not part of the collection), 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 65)
    Turner, Eva at 155 East 77th street.
  - Russian Gipsy Songs, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 66)
    Including two by Plevitzkaya
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Letzte Lieder, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 67)
    (Taped from discs) Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano
  - Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948. Andrea Chénier, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 68)
    Milanov, Zinka, soprano; Tucker, Richard, 1913-1975, tenor; Warren, Leonard, 1911-1960, baritone; Corena, Fernando, bass; Lipton, Martha, mezzo-soprano. Metropolitan Opera House.
  - Interview with Leonard, Bill. UN program on Malaria and Leprocy. (Not part of ARS collection), 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 69)
    Theodore, Fagan, interviewer
  - Tansman, Alexandre, 1897-1986. Serment, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Massini, Galleano, singer, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 71)
    (Taped from discs) Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Manon Lescaut. Ah! Manon, mi tradisce il tuo folle pensier; Tosca. Recondita armonia; E lucevan le stelle -- Adriana Lecouvreur. Dolcissima effigie; Anima ho stanca -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda. Celeste Aïda -- Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948. Fedora. Amor ti vieta; Madre, la mia vecchia madre; Fante mi svela l'immondo ritrovo; Andrea Chénier. Si, fui soldato; Come un bel dì di maggio -- Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana. Mamma, quel vino è generoso
  - Salzburger Festspiele. Bruckner, Anton, 1824-1896. Te Deum 1960, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 72)
    Price, Leontyne, soprano; Rössl-Majdan, Hilde, contralto; Wunderlich, Fritz, 1930-1966, tenor; Berry, Walter, 1859-1927, bass-baritone; Wächter, Eberhard, basse. Sauer, F., organ. Wiener Philharmoniker and Singverein der Musikfreunde. Karajan, Herbert von, conductor
  - Rehearsal with Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 73)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Entführung aus dem Serail
  - Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 Songs, 7" reel (Box 8, Folder 74)
    Baumann, Mordecai, baritone; Victor, Ernest, pianoforte. Arne, Michael, 1741?-1786. Love's labour's lost. When daisies pied -- Vernon, Joseph, 1737 or 8-1782. Twelfth night. When that I was a tiny boy -- Stephen, R. J. S. Much ado about nothing. Sigh no more ladies -- Morley, Thomas, 1557-1603?. As you like it. It was a lover and his lass -- Arne, Michael, 1741?-1786. Love's labour's lost. When icicles hang on the wall; As you like it. Blow thou winter's wind -- Smith, J. C. Tempest. No more dams for fish I'll make -- Arne, Michael, 1741?-1786. As you like it. Under the Greenwood tree; Tempest. Where the bee sucks; Twelfth night. Come away death
  - Bass and Baritones III, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 75)
    (Taped from discs) Hüsch, Gerhard, baritone. Kilpinen, Yrjö. Tunturilauluja; Am Kirchenstrande; An das LIed -- Loewe, Carl, 1796-1869. Gedichte, op. 62. Süsses Begräbnis; Tom der Reimer -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Dass sie hier gewesen -- Panzéra, Charles, 1896-1976, baritone. Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Also hat Gott die Welt geliebt -- Schorr, Friedrich, 1888-1953, bass-baritone. Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Elias. Selections -- Schlusnus, Heinrich, 1888-1952, baritone -- Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Knaben Wunderhorn. Rheinlegendchen; Tamboursg'sell -- Schorr, Friedrich, 1888-1953, bass-baritone. Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Biterolf -- Janssen, Herbert, baritone. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 29. Traum durch die Dämmerung -- Schützendorf, Leo, 1886-1931. Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia. A un dottor della mia sorte -- Christoff, Boris, bass. Russian songs. Shrove Tuesday; Lumberjack's Song; Ukrainian Love Song; Down the Street; Going down the Volga; Lonely Autumn Night
  - Bass and Baritones, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 76)
    (Taped from discs) Forsell, John, 1868-1941, baritone. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Deh viene alla finestra -- Bohnen, Michael, bass-baritone -- Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Robert le diable. Nonnes, qui reposez -- Plançon, Pol, 1854-1914, bass. Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Stabat Mater, G minor. Pro peccatis -- Panzéra, Charles, 1896-1976, baritone. Duparc, Henri, 1848-1933. Soupir -- Nissen, Hans Hermann, bass-baritone. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. Auf wolkigen Höh'n wohnen die Götter; Rheingold. Abendlich strahlt der Sonne Auge; Freund
  - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Samson et Dalila Apr. 12, 1958, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 77)
    Stevens, Risë, 1913-, mezzo-soprano; Del Monaco, Mario, 1915-1982, tenor; Singher, Martial, baritone; Tozzi, Giorgio, bass; Scott, Norman, 1921-1968, bass; Corelli, Franco, tenor; Nagy, Robert, 1929-, tenor. Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.). Orchestra
  - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Samson et Dalila Apr. 12, 1958, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Pianoforte Records. Historic, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 79)
    (Taped from discs) Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943, piano. Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Rhapsodies hongroises. No 2 -- Rosenthal, Moriz, 1862-1946, piano. Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Preludes, piano, op. 28. No. 11; No.6; No. 23; No. 7; No. 8; Pachmann, Vladimir de, 1848-1933, piano. Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Waltz, piano, op. 64, no. 1, D? major
  - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci Jan. 3, 1958, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 80)
    Del Monaco, Mario, 1915-1982, tenor; Amara, Lucine, soprano; Warren, Leonard, 1911-1960, baritone. Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.). Orchestra. Mitropoulos, Dimitri, 1896-1960, conductor
  - Debicka, Hedwig von, soprano, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 81)
    (Taped from discs) Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen. Parle-moi de ma mère -- Schlusnus, Heinrich, 1888-1952, tenor; Rosvænge, Helge, 1897-1972, tenor; Handl, Herma, soprano; Jungkurth, Hedwig, 1900-, soprano. Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Selections -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto. V'ho ingannato -- Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci. Selection -- Rosvænge, Helge, 1897-1972, tenor; Leisner, Emmi, contralto; Waltzke (sic). Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883. Martha. Schlafe wohl! -- Rosvænge, Helge, 1897-1972, tenor. Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. Miserere; Domgraf-Fassbaender, Willi, baritone. Rigoletto. Lassù, in cielo; Deh non parlare al misero
  - Interview with Tourel, Jennie on mezzo-soprano singing, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 82)
    Stignani, Ebe, mezzo-soprano. Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Favorite. O mon Fernand -- Simionato, Giulietta, mezzo-soprano. Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon. Connais-tu le pays? -- Stevens, Risë, 1913-, mezzo-soprano. Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Samson et Dalila. Amour! viens aider ma faiblesse! -- Tourel, Jennie. Rossini, Gioachino, 1792-1868. Italiana in Algeri, L'. Cruda sorte -- Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880. Contes d'Hoffmann. Barcarolle -- Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Cenerentola. Non più mesta
  - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust.c. 1910, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 83)
    (Taped from discs) Selections with various of singers
  - Wagnerian Fragment, 5" reel (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre ca. 1937, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 85)
    (Taped from discs)
  - Farrell, Eileen, 1920-2002, sopranoMay 23, 1948, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 86)
    Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826. Oberon. Ocean, thou mighty monster -- Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886. Gioconda. Suicidio -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ernani. Ernani, Ernani, involami -- Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Jeanne d' Ark. Adieu, forêts (Orleanskaia deva. Ariia Ioanny) -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Ariadne auf Naxos. Slection --
  - Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Evgenii Onegin 1958, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 87)
    Amara, Lucine, soprano; Tucker, Richard, 1869-1942, tenor; Guarrera, Frank, 1923-, baritone; Tozzi, Giorgio, bass. Metropolitan Opera House Chorus and Orchestra.
  - Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Manon Lescaut Jan. 19, 1959, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 88)
    Tebaldi, Renata as Manon Lescaut; Tucker, Richard, 1913-1975, as des Grieux; Anthony, Charles, 1929-, as de Morfontaine; Guarrera, Frank, 1923, as Lescaut; Flagello, Ezio as Geronte; Cehanovsky, George, 1892-1986, as the innkeeper. Metropolitan Opera House Chorus and Orchestra. Cleva, Fausto, conductor
  - Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Manon Lescaut Jan. 19, 1959, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Midsummer night's dream (Part II), 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 90)
    Parts 1 and 3 on tape 679 or Fagan's numbering XXXVI Deller, Alfred, as Oberon; Vyvyan, Jennifer, 1925-1974, as Titania; Massine, Leonide, 1896-, as Puck; Brannigan, Owen, as Bottom; Longsten, E., as Quince; Pears, Peter, Sir, as Flute; Kelley, David, 1932-, as Snug; Biles, Eric, as Snout; Ward, Joseph, 1942-, as Starveling; Marron, G, as Lysander; Thomas, Marjorie, as Hermia; Helmsley, T., as Demetrius; Cantelo, April, as Helena; Robinson, F., as Theseus; Peters, Joanne K. A., as Hyppolita. English Opera Group Orchestra. Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976, conductor
  - Lehmann, Lotte, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 91)
    (Taped from discs) Various opera selctions and Lieder
  - Instrumentalists and odds and ends, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Auber, D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871. Fra Diavolo. Highlights, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 93)
    Sénéchal, Michel, tenor
  - Coward, Sir Noël, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 94)
    Senorita Nina; Whatever became of (unpublished version); Surrey with a fringe on top; Let's do it (some of the verses unpublished)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concerto, piano, K. 40, D major, 5" reel (Box 9, Folder 95)
    Balsam, Artur, 1906-1994, piano. Netherlands Philharmonic Orchestra. Ackerman, Otto, 1909-1960, conductor
  - Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Alexander Nevsky (Cantata) Russian., 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Tourel, Jennie, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 98)
    (Taped from discs) Vocal selections
  - Spoken, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 99)
    Advertisement for Columbia records from 1908 -- Beerbohm Tree, Henry, Sir. Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Selections. Julius Caesar; King Richard II; Merry wives of Windsor; Hamlet; Trilby [sic] -- Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931. First words spoken into phonograph (recreated in 1927) -- Sullivan, Arthur, 1932-, Speech recorded on Oct. 5, 1888. Originally on white wax cylinder
  - Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. Carnaval romain and Francs-juges, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Gilels, Emil plays at the United Nations, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 101)
    Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Concerto, piano, no. 1, op. 23, B? minor.
  - Farrell, Eileen, 1920-2002, soprano. Soundrack from the film Interrupted Melody., 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 102)
    (Taped from discs) Mostly opera selections
  - May, Elaine, 1932-; Nichols, Mike, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Baritone to Tenor. Zanelli, Renato, 1892-1935, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Russell, Anna, singer, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 105)
    (No further info. on tape or index card)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. Part III, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 106)
    (Taped from discs) Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962 as Isolde; Suthaus, Ludwig as Tristan
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Mosè in Egitto, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 107)
    Filippeschi, Mario as Amenofi; Lazzari, Agostino as Elisero; Rossi-Lemeni, Nicola, 1920- as Mosè; Taddei, Giuseppe as Pharaoh; Danieli, Lucia as Maria; Rizzoli, Bruna; De Palma, Piero; Mancini, Caterina.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. Part I, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. Part II, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Mosè in Egitto, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Mosè in Egitto, 7" reel (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Party Spoken, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 112)
    Portions -- This is no shit -- Lewis & Martin commercial -- Suitcase -- Boy next door -- Greek doctor
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata Jan. 24, 1959, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 113)
    Albanese, Licia as Violeta; Vanni, Helen as Flora; Cehanovsky, George, 1892-1986 as d' Obigny; Marsh, Calvin as Baron Douphol; Sgarro, Louis, 1920-1985 as Dr. Grenville; Carelli, Gabor as Gaston; Valetti, Cesare as Alfredo; Allen, Mildred as Annina; Marcelle, Lou as Giuseppe; Sereni, Mario as Germond; Treby, John as the gardener. Metropolitan Opera House Chorus and Orchestra. Adler, Kurt, 1907-1977, conductor
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. MacbethFeb. 21, 1959, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 114)
    Warren, Leonard, 1911-1960, baritone; Rysanek, Leonie, soprano; Hines, Jerome, 1921-, bass; Sternberg, Harold, singer; Bergonzi, Carlo, tenor; Olvis, William, singer; Hawkins, Osie, baritone; Marsh, Calvin, singer; Cundari, Emilia, singer; Allen, Mildred, singer; Pechner, Gerhard, baritone; Ordassy, Carlotta, singer. Metropolitan Opera House Chorus and Orchestra, Leinsdorf, Erich, 1912-1993 conductor
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. MacbethFeb. 21, 1959, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Instrumentals I, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 116)
    (Taped from discs) Mainly Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Instrumentals II, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Instrumentals III, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - United Nations Staff Day1954, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 119)
    Opening remarks, Secretary General -- Recreation Chairman remarks -- UN Singers -- White, Lou, organ -- Warfield, William, bass. Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Giulio Cesare. Selections -- Spirituals. Ol' Man River -- Elman, Mischa, 1891-1967, violin. Sammartini, Giovanni Battista, 1700 (ca.)-1775. Passacaglia -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Concerto, violin & string orchestra, D minor. 2nd and 3rd movements -- Holme, Celeste -- Gopal, Ram; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993; Meiser, Edith, 1898-1993. Anderson. M. Scenes from Mary of Scotland -- Bergen, Edgar; McCarthy, Charlie; Snerd, Mortimer -- White, Lou, organ -- Whiteman, Paul. Jazz -- Borge, Victor
  - United Nations Human Rights Day ConcertDec. 8, 1958, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 120)
    Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 100, B? major. New York Philharmonic Orchestra. Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990, conductor
  - United Nations Human Rights Day ConcertDec. 8, 1958, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Violinists of the past, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 122)
    Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Zigeunerweisen; Tarantella -- Passini, violin [?]Kubelík, Jan. Dance of the Gnomes (1904)
  - Björling, Jussi, 1911-1960, tenor, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 123)
    Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Cäcilie; Morgen -- Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948. Fedora. Amor ti vieta -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto. Questa o quella per me pari sono -- Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Turandot. Nessun dorma -- Hardelot, Guy d', 1858-1936. Because -- Lehár, Franz, 1838-1898. Das Land des Lächelns. Du bist mein ganzes Herz -- Borodin, Aleksandr Porfir' evich, 1833-1887. Prince Igor. Selection -- Laparra, Raoul, 1876-1943. Ilustre Fregona. Serenata -- Strauss, Johann, 1804-1849. Zigeunerbaron. Wer uns getraut -- Attenberg. Faval. I maener ever lag
  - Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835. Pirata, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 124)
    Callas, Maria, 1923-1977, soprano. American Opera Association. Carnegie Hall
  - Ferrier, Kathleen, 1912-1953, contralto 1949, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 125)
    Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962, piano. Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Frauenliebe und Leben. Edinburgh Festival
  - Instrumental1959, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 126)
    Marcello, Alessandro, 1669-1747. Concerto, oboe, strings, continuo, C minor -- Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741. Concerto, bassoon & string orchestra, F. VIII, 5, D minor. London Symphony Orchestra. Ansermet, Ernest, 1883-1969, conductor
  - Panameñan Folklore. Part I, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 127)
    Capricho Típico Panameño. Galimany, Alberto -- Charpentier, Eduardo. Fantasia Nacional. Potpurri -- Montorio, Daniel. Mejorana. Orquesta de Cámara de Madrid -- Punto. Coco. Conjunto Aires Tableños -- Tamborito. Ajé mi pajarito -- Tuna. Girandó
  - Anders, Peter, 1908-1954, tenor, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 128)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Entführung aus dem Serail. Hier soll ich dich denn sehen; Wenn der Freude Tränen fliessen; O wie ängstlich, o wie feurig -- Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883. Martha. Selection -- Nicolai, Karl. Die LustigeWeiber von Windsor. Horch, die Lerche singt im Hain -- Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Elisir d'amore. Furtiva lagrima -- Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Fanciulla del West. Ch'ella mi creda libero e lontano -- Manon Lescaut. Donna non vidi mai.
  - Mexican Folklore Part IIApril 21, 1959, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 129)
    Recorded live. Estado de Chiapas. Gobernador y gobernadora. Baile de las Chiapanecas -- Estado de Jalisco. Charra. Jarabe Tapatio -- Estado de Michoacan. Tipos Indigenas; Danza de los Moros -- Estado de Veracruz. Indias Papantecas; Sones jarochos por el Conjunto Tierra Blanca -- Estado de Oaxaca. Chinantecas; Baile de La Sandunga; Danza de la Pluma; Mesa Central. Modelos Otomies; Ritual Otomi "Ofrenda"; Danza Azteca. Marquez, Luis M., artistic director; Barreiro, Plutarco J., music; Escoto, Jorge G, choreography.
  - Cantos del Anahuac. Primitive songs of Mexico on original instruments., 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 130)
    Performers: Salas, Marti; Los Primitivos. Works: Xtoles. (Maya) -- Goi. Danza Guerrera -- Mowali. Invocacion a la tierra y la lluvia. Papago -- Danza a Huehueteotl, Dios del Fuego -- Invocacion a Chaac, Dios de la Lluvia (Lacandon) -- Danza popular La Sardinita (Seri) -- Invocacion a los cuatro puntos cardinales (Otomi) -- Fanfarras con trompetas de Caracol -- Cantar Victorioso
  - United Nations Staff Day1953, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 131)
    List, Eugene,piano. Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Preludes, piano, book 2. Feux d'artifice -- Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Rhapsodies hongroises. No 6 -- Hammerskjold, Dag -- Baccaloni, Salvatore, 1900-1969, bass. Somano, Franco, piano. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Don Giovanni. Madamina, il catalogo è questo -- Some enchanted evening -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Falstaff. Quand'ero paggio del Duca di Norfolk -- Hammerskjold, Dag -- Anderson, Marian, 1897-1993, contralto. Rupf, Franz, piano. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Forelle (Song); Erlkönig -- He's got the whole world in his hand -- Hammerskjold, Dag -- Kaye, Danny -- Merrill, Robert, 1917-2004, baritone -- Sayão, Bidú, soprano -- Templeton, Alec, 1910-1963
  - Joan Sutherland, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 132)
    Dalayrac, Nicolas-Marie. Quand la bien aimée reviendra -- Bononcini, Giovanni, 1670-1747. Griselda. Per la gloria d'adorarvi -- Boyce, William, 1711-1779. Solomon. Tell me lovely shepherd -- Arne, Michael, 1741?-1786. Love in a village. Traveller benighted -- Paisiello, Giovanni, 1740-1816. Molinara. Nel cor più non mi sento -- Bonynge, Richard, iano. Shield, William, 1748-1829. Rosina. Selections -- Arditi, Luigi, 1822-1903. Bacio
  - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 133)
    (Taped from discs) Journet, Marcel as Mefisto
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Messa da Requiem, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - UN Various Cuts. Specials, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 135)
    Dowing, Jerry -- Cuba [illegible] -- Pakistan interruption -- "shit" -- [illegible] riots -- OPEX -- [illegible]; Cowelly -- 1953 interruption -- GA - Nepal interruption -- Macmillan and Dag -- London -- Barudi -- Bull -- Menon [?] Cats -- Wachinku Lizoids [?] -- Iran question -- Wachinku [?] gets old -- US [illegible] -- Africa story; 2nd committee -- Vote -- Cap Verdeimes [?]
  - Grétry, André Ernest Modeste, 1741-1813. Richard C ur-de-Lion. Highlights, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - Mexican Folklore. Part I, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 137)
    Continuation on tape 129
  - Baillie, Isobel, 1895-, soprano. (See also III), 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 138)
    Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934. Kingdom. Sun goeth down -- Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Messiah. I know that my Redeemer liveth
  - Ballets, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 139)
    Adam, Adolphe, 1803-1856. Giselle -- Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Piano music. Selections; arr. Sylphides -- Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Romeo i Dzhul' etta (Ballet) -- Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974. B uf sur le toit -- Gaîté parisienne -- Valse -- Danse
  - Basses and Baritones I, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 140)
    (Taped from discs) Miscellaneous opera selections
  - Basses and Baritones II, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Rheingold, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 142)
    Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962, soprano
  - Panameñan Folklore. Part II, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 143)
    (Continued from tape 127) Mejorana Santeña. Conjunto Alma Panameña -- Margarita Rodadora (Tambor) -- Santo Domingo (Danzón, Cumbia) -- Santeña (Mejorana) -- Mejorana Zapateada -- Saloma de mi Tierra (Tonada) -- Decimas Interioranas (Mesano. Plicet, Tobias; Acevedo, Mercedes)
  - Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809. Various instrumental scraps, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 144)
  - About Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier., 5" reel (Box 10, Folder 145)
  - Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon. I May 15, 1937, 7" reel (Box 10, Folder 146)